致命魔术
你在仔细看吗?
Are you watching closely?
每一场魔术表演都有三个步骤
Every magic trick consists of three parts, or acts.
第一个步骤是"以虚代实"
The first part is called "the pledge."
魔术师秀出一个真实的东西
The magician shows you something ordinary.
一副牌 一只鸟或一个人
A deck of cards, a bird or a man.
让你看这样东西
He shows you this object.
叫你检视它
Perhaps he asks you to inspect it,
看它的确是真的
to see that it is indeed real,
平常的不得了
unaltered, normal.
但是 其中一定有假
But, of course, it probably isn't.
你想去哪里?
Where do you think you're going?
我是表演的一部分 猪头
I'm part of the bloody act, you fool.
第二个步骤是"偷天换日"
The second act is called "the turn."
魔术师利用这个普通的东西
The magician takes the ordinary something
做出令人叹为观止的表演
and makes it do something extraordinary.
现在你很想找出秘诀 但是绝对找不到
Now you're looking for the secret, but you won't find it,
因为你根本没有真正在看
because, of course, you're not really looking.
你并不是真的想知道
You don't really want to know.
你想要被...骗
You want to be... fooled.
但是你还不会鼓掌
But you wouldn't clap yet,
因为把东西变不见还不够
because making something disappear isn't enough.
你必须把它变回来
You have to bring it back.
所以魔术都有第三个步骤
That's why every magic trick has a third act.
最难的部分
The hardest part.
我们称之为...
The part we call...
..."惊天动地"
..."the prestige."
惊天动地?罗伯特安杰 你的雇主丹顿大师
The prestige? And did Robert Angier, the Great Danton, your employer,
那晚有完成表演吗?
get to that final part of his trick that night?
- 并没有 出了状况 - 出了什么状况?
- No, sir. Something went wrong. - What went wrong?
我看到有个人跑到舞台下方
I saw someone making their way below stage.
我跟踪他
I followed him.
那是波登 眼睁睁看着安先生溺死
It was Borden, watching Mr. Angier drown.
柯特先生 请向陪审团说明你的职业
Would you please describe your occupation to the jury, Mr. Cutter.
我是机关师 设计魔术表演
I'm an engineer, I design illusions
打造需要的道具和机关
and construct the apparatus necessary for performing them.
柯先生 舞台下方的水箱
So, Mr. Cutter, was this water-filled tank beneath the stage
也是这个魔术的道具吗?
part of Mr. Angier's illusion?
不 水箱是第一个表演用的
No. The tank was brought on for the first trick
然后就被搬下台
and then taken offstage.
一定是波登把它移到机关门底下了
Borden must have placed it under the trap door after the end of it.
水箱有多大?
How large was this tank?
表演水底脱逃的一般大小
It's a normal tank for escape under water,
大约四 五百加仑吧
about 400 or 500 gallons.
波登怎么能一个人移动水箱
How do you think he was able to move the tank
而没有让任何人发现?
under the trap door without anyone noticing?
他是魔术师 你去问他
He's a magician, ask him.
我要求你为我解释
I ask again,
安先生的魔术机关
would this man explain the mechanics of Mr. Angier's illusion.
真正的遁移术
The Real Transported Man is one of the most sought after illusions
是这一行最抢手的魔术
in this business.
出售秘诀的权利在我手中
I have the right to sell it on.
如果被揭穿就不值钱了
If I reveal the method here, the trick is worthless.
我们怎么知道水箱不只是
How can we know that the tank wasn't simply
单纯出错?
some part of the trick that went wrong?
我了解你的处境
Mr. Cutter, I see your predicament.
但是这攸关波登的生死
But Alfred Borden's life hangs in the balance.
如果你私底下向我透露细节
If you were prepared to disclose the details to me in private,
我就能对此案做出中肯的判决
I might be able to judge their relevance to the case.
你能接受这种妥协吗?
Might this be an acceptable compromise?
麻烦你掏出口袋里的东西
I'm going to have to ask you to turn out your pockets.
我不是故意找你碴 典狱长去年在曼彻斯特看过
Not my idea, sir. The warden saw his show in Manchester last year
他凭空消失的表演
where he vanished into thin air.
他觉得他会企图逃狱
He's convinced he'll try and escape.
我说他能逃走的唯一机会
I told him the only way Borden's going to disappear
就是和其它囚犯混在一起
is if I leave him out there with the other inmates.
检查手铐的锁...
Check the locks...
...检查两次
...twice.
我叫欧文
My name is Owens.
我是一名律师
I'm a solicitor.
代表卡德洛爵士 一位业余魔术师兼历史学家...
I represent Lord Caldlow, an accomplished amateur magician and...
多少钱?
How much?
- 卡爵士有兴趣... - 他出多少钱买我的魔术?
- He is interested... - How much for my tricks?
五千英镑
Five thousand pounds.
跟我的机关师法隆说钱归他
Talk to Fallon, my engineer. Money's for him.
我说了 他答应出售你的秘诀
Yes, I did. He offered to sell me your tricks.
除了最值钱的遁移术外
All except the most valuable one, The Transported Man.
我绝不会出售我最伟大的魔术
Well, I won't forgive myself for selling my greatest trick.
即使是为了你女儿?
Even for your daughter?
如果报纸没料错 你会被判死刑 你女儿就需要别人照顾
If the newspaper is right and you are for the drop, your daughter is going to need looking after.
法隆会照顾她
Fallon will take care of her.
伯纳法隆
Perfect, Fallon.
他这个人跟你一样神秘
A man with a past as obscure as your own.
法院一定会剥夺他的监护权 你女儿就会变成孤儿
The courts have motioned she be removed from his care. She will be an orphan.
你应该对童工工厂很熟吧
I know you're no stranger to the workhouse.
会比监狱好吗?
It's better than here?
我给你一个机会维护尊严
I'm offering you a way to wrap up your affairs with dignity.
也给你女儿一个未来
I'm offering your daughter a future.
她被卡爵士领养 保证要什么...
As Lord Caldlow's ward, she will want for nothing...
...就有什么
...ever.
好好考虑吧
Well, think it over.
爵士给你这本日记
And Lord Caldlow would like you to have this,
以表诚意 也许你会有兴趣
as a show of good faith. It might be of interest.
这是罗伯特安杰的日记 包括他在科罗拉多
Robert Angier's diary, including the time he spent in Colorado
学会你的魔术
learning your trick.
- 他没学会我的魔术 - 真的吗?
- He never learned it. - Really?
他回来以后表演全新的遁移术
On his return, he mounted a version of The Transported Man
报纸说比你的原版更棒
that the papers said was better even than your original.
你想知道安杰的秘密
If you want Angier's secrets,
得把他从坟墓挖出来问
you go dig him up and ask him yourself.
我想要你的秘密 波登
I want your secret, Mr. Borden.
为你的女儿着想吧
Consider your daughter.
字谜
A cipher,
一个大谜团...
an enigma...
...寻找
...a search,
我要寻找答案
a search for answers.
就算科罗拉多是我的终点站
Even if Colorado is the end of my journey,
要解开波登的谜要花
it'll take much longer to unravel
更久的时间
the rest of Borden's secrets.
他笔记的密码
See, the cipher in his notebook is
只有一个字
unlocked by a single word,
但也得要花好几个月翻译
but it will still take months to translate his writing.
才能了解他的想法
And to know his mind.
我的执着经得起这场考验
Well, my passion is equal to the task.
科罗拉多泉
安先生? 欢迎光临泉镇
Mr. Angier, welcome to Colorado Springs.
- 整座小镇都有供电吗? - 是的
- The whole town has electricity. - Yes, sir.
好...
Well...
...隆重的欢迎
...quite a reception.
您是本季第一位客人 安先生
You're our first guest of the season, Mr. Angier.
您的电报没提到您会待多久
Your telegram didn't indicate how long you'd be staying with us.
能待多久就待多久
For as long as it takes.
我明天需要马车载我上山
I will need a coach tomorrow to take me up the mountain.
山顶关闭了
Well, the peak's closed, sir.
为了科学实验
For scientific experimentation.
我知道
Yes, I know.
这就是我来的目的
That's why I'm here.
哇呜 哇呜
Whoa. Whoa.
先生 接下来您得自己走路了
You'll have to walk the rest, I'm afraid, sir.
极度危险
有电危险
严禁擅自入内
令人惊讶 你们记者
I'm amazed how many of you newspaper writers
都看不懂我的标志吗
can't read my sign.
看来我并不受欢迎
Not the welcome I was expecting.
我认得你
I know you.
你是魔术大师丹顿
You're the Great Danton.
我在伦敦看了你七场表演
I saw your show in London.
你猜中观众
Seven times you guessed every object
口袋里的每样东西
the audience had in their pockets.
我是艾利 围栏的事真抱歉 太多人来干扰
I'm Alley. Sorry about the fence. People keep interfering with our work.
- 我来见泰斯拉 - 为什么?
- I've come to see Tesla. - Why?
他为我的同行打造一架机器
He made a machine for a colleague of mine some time ago.
- 你能安排我们见面吗? - 恐怕是不太可能
- Can you get me a meeting with him? - Impossible, I'm afraid.
我带了很多钱来
I've brought a lot of money.
很抱歉 安先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Angier.
我帮不上忙
I simply can't help.
我会一直待在旅馆
I'll be staying at the hotel, indefinitely.
我现在握着什么?
Hey, what am I holding?
你的怀表
Your watch.
波登的日记 1897年4月3日
Borden's journal entry for April 3, 1897,
记录了奥芬大剧院的演出
describes a show at the Orpheum Theater.
那时我们才刚认识
That was just days after he first met me.
当时我们都是刚出道的魔术师
We were two young men at the start of a great career,
我们完全献身于魔术
two young men devoted to an illusion,
从没有想要伤害任何人
two young men who never intended to hurt anyone.
谁有胆量上台
Which of you brave souls
绑住这位美女?
is willing to bind this lovely young woman?
我!
Me!
绑住她的手腕
If you would tie her wrists,
绑住她的腿...
bind her feet...
...脚踝也要绑紧
...around the ankle.
你们是水手吗?
Are either of you two gentlemen sailors?
- 不是 - 不是
- No. - No.
我想你们打的结应该都很紧
I'm sure you can both tie a strong knot.
他太自满 毫无创意 又无趣
He's complacent, he's predictable, he's boring.
米尔顿很成功
Milton has gotten success, whatever that means,
但现在他很没种 不敢再冒任何风险
so now he's scared. He won't take any risks at all.
糟蹋观众的热情
He's squandering the goodwill of his audience with tired,
- 他耍二流把戏... - 大家爱看这些把戏
- second-rate tricks... - They're all favorites.
拜托 让我试些新魔术吧 他甚至不敢尝试"接子弹"
Give me something fresh. He won't even try a bloody bullet catch.
"接子弹"是自杀
A bullet catch is suicide.
要是志愿者放钮扣进去就死定了
All it takes is some smartass volunteer to put a button in the barrel.
- 那就用暗桩 - 不能每个魔术都用暗桩
- Use a plant. - You can't for every trick.
不然客人就没位置坐了
No seats left for the punters.
好吧 不表演"接子弹" 重点是好魔术师
All right, no bullet catch, whatever, but the point is a real magician
会不断创新戏法
tries to invent something new
让其他魔术师想破脑袋
that other magicians will scratch their heads over.
然后你就能靠它小赚一笔
Then you sell it to him for a small fortune.
- 什么? - 我猜你有惊人绝技?
- What? - I suppose you have such a trick?
- 没错 - 你能卖给我吗?
- I sure do. - Would you care to sell it to me?
不行 只有我做得到
No. No one else can do my trick.
- 每个魔术都能被模仿 对吧? - 错了
- Any trick can be duplicated. - Wrong.
如果波登发明了他的杰作
If Mr. Borden has invented his masterpiece,
大概只有他有办法演出
he's prepared to do it.
米尔顿很会作秀 但波登说得对
Milton is a showman, but Borden is right,
米尔顿不肯冒险
he won't get his hands dirty.
你若想看真正的魔术
If you want to see what it takes to make real magic,
就去天利剧院 有位中国魔术师很厉害
go to the Tenley. There's a Chinaman there and he really has what it takes.
- 他叫钟林苏 - 门票太贵 我看不起
- Chung Ling Soo. - I can't afford that.
我认识看门的家伙
I know the bloke run the door.
你们俩去看吧 谁看出
You two go and see that show, and whichever one of you can tell me
他的金鱼缸戏法窍门 就有奖赏
how he does the goldfish bowl trick gets the prize.
- 什么奖赏? - 试演一段魔术
- Which is? - Ten minutes onstage
在我的老朋友艾克曼面前
with my old friend, Mr. Ackerman.
- 真的假的? - 艾克曼是谁?
- Really? - Who's Ackerman?
伦敦的顶尖经纪人
The top theatrical agent in London.
- 我看到你绳结没打好 - 我的手腕动了一下
- I saw you drop the knot again. - I turned my wrists.
你一直没搞懂 是吧?
Some nights you just don't get it, do you?
要是绳结松掉
I mean, if that knot slips and Julia's on the hoist,
茱莉亚就会摔断腿
she'll break her leg.
你教的绳结有问题
It's the wrong knot.
我说过 蓝氏结比较牢固
Like I said, the Langford double will hold tighter.
蓝氏结不能碰到水 太危险了
The Langford double isn't a wet knot. It's too dangerous.
要是绳子膨胀她就无法松绑
If the rope swells, she can't slip it.
- 我可以在水底松脱蓝氏结 - 她做得到 可以练习
- I can slip a Langford underwater. - We can practice.
- 波登 他说不行 - 你对绳结懂得比我多吗?
- Borden, he said no. - Oh, you know knots better than me?
听好 不准再出错
Listen, no more mistakes.
是吗? 你想取代我?
All right. Yeah? Do you? You want to take over?
- 你走吧 - 想都别想
- Just leave. - I didn't think so.
柯特 他打哪儿来的?
Hey, Cutter, where's he from?
你打哪儿来的? 他以前帮魔术师佛吉搬道具
Where are you from? He shifts props for Virgil at the hall.
- 你不担心他偷学你的魔术? - 他只想创造全新魔术
- Worried he'll steal your tricks? - Doesn't deal in methods.
- 你怎么知道?- 因为我雇他
- How do you know? - Because I hired him
去偷学佛吉的柳橙戏法
to find out how Virgil does the orange trick.
- 我不信任他 - 他是天生魔术师
- I don't trust him. - He's a natural magician.
当然不能信任
'Course you can't trust him.
我觉得波登没问题
I think he's all right.
- 你觉得大家都没问题 - 连你也一样
- You think everyone's all right. - Even you.
安杰 注意一点 就连我都看得到你亲老婆的腿
Watch your sightlines. If I can see you kiss your wife's leg every night,
前排的观众一定也看得到!
so can the blokes at the ends of rows three and four!
你错了 不可能
You're wrong. It can't be.
- 你看看他 - 这就是他的秘诀
- Look at the man. - This is the trick.
这是他的表演
This is the performance. Right here.
难怪没人看穿他的秘密
This is why no one can detect his method.
他对魔术完全奉献
Total devotion to his art.
彻底自我牺牲
A lot of self-sacrifice.
你懂吗
You know.
这是扬名立万的...
It's the only way to escape...
...唯一方法 知道吗?
...all this, you know?
这很难夹起来 而且还没有装水
I can barely lift this thing and it's not even filled with water.
也没有金鱼 你看
Or fish, look.
我不确定行不行 等一下
I don't know. Hang on a second.
他一定壮得跟条牛一样
He must be strong as an ox.
这么多年来他一直假装跛脚
He's been pretending to be a cripple for years.
每次他出门面对大众都得装 不可思议
Any time he's in public, any time he goes out. It's unthinkable.
有一次波登看到他露出马脚 我没办法这样
Borden saw it at once. But I couldn't fathom it.
很难想像花一辈子去假装别人
Living my whole life pretending to be someone else.
你是在假装啊
You are pretending to be someone else.
换个名字并不算吧
I don't think changing a name compares.
不知是名字 你也换了身分和来历
Not your name. Who you are and where you're from.
因为我答应不能败坏家人名声
I promised I wouldn't embarrass my family with my theatrical endeavors.
我帮你想到一个艺名
I thought of a name for you.
魔术大师丹顿
The Great Danton.
你喜欢吗? 这名字很炫
Do you like it? But it's sophisticated.
那是法国人名
It's French.
波登觉得只有他了解魔术的本质
Borden writes as if no one but he understood the true nature of magic.
但是他了解自我牺牲吗?
But what does he know of self-sacrifice?
你这笨蛋
You bloody fool.
- 他杀了小鸟 - 没事的
- He killed it. - It's OK.
- 小鸟死了 - 没有啦
- He killed it. - He didn't.
瞧 他会把他变回来
Look, now he'll bring it back.
- 不 他杀了小鸟 - 他没有
- No, he killed it. - No, he didn't.
看到没? 他没事 他很好
Look, see, he's all right. He's fine.
- 看到没 - 那他的兄弟呢?
- Look at him. - But where's his brother?
你儿子真是聪明
He's a sharp lad, your son.
他是我外甥
Oh, he's my nephew.
噢
Ah.
算你今天走运
You're the lucky one today.
你在仔细看吗?
Are you watching closely?
看清楚了
Look closer.
绝对不要揭穿谜底
Never show anyone.
他们会求你 奉承你
They'll beg you and flatter you for the secret,
一旦你说出来 你就没有利用价值了
but as soon as you give it up, you'll be nothing to them.
懂吗? 一文不值
You understand? Nothing.
魔术的秘密没啥了不起
The secret impresses no one.
变魔术的技巧才重要
The trick you use it for is everything.
谢谢你请客 波登先生
Well, thank you for lunch, Mr. Borden.
不客气
You're welcome.
艾佛 叫我艾佛
Alfred, it's Alfred.
艾佛
Alfred.
我很想进去喝杯茶
So I could use a cup of tea.
我怕... 我怕房东说闲话 最好不要...
I can't allow... It's the landlord. It's not...
你以为...这样我就进不去?
You think that's... Is that enough to keep me out?
我想是吧
I think so.
我们会再见面吧?
So I'll see you again?
牛奶或糖?
Milk and sugar?
那是什么东西?
What's in there?
安杰的机关
Angier's machine.
科罗拉多泉
这是你打造的吗?
You built this, Mr. Cutter?
不 这不是魔术师打造的
Oh, no, sir. This wasn't built by a magician.
这是天才的杰作
This was built by a wizard.
他能让魔术师的戏法成真
A man who can actually do what magicians pretend to do.
法官大人 这些道具会怎么处理?
Tell me, Your Honor, what happens with these things after the trial?
卖给卡德洛爵士
They've been sold to a Lord Caldlow.
一个狂热的收藏家 他对这案子很有兴趣
An avid collector, very interested in the case.
千万别让他拿走这样东西
Yeah. Well, don't let him take this.
- 为什么? - 太危险了
- Why ever not? - It's too dangerous.
它只是造型很炫
I'm sure beneath its bells and whistles
但功能很简单
it's got a simple and disappointing trick.
的确是简单得令人失望
The most disappointing of all, sir.
因为这不是魔术
It has no trick.
这是真的
It's real.
这就是淹死安杰的水箱?
This is the tank Angier drowned in?
是的
Yes.
这就是机关...
This is the...
...魔术师的手穿过这里
...place where the performer's hand reaches through
打开假锁
to the trick padlock.
标准的魔术脱逃机关?
A standard magical apparatus for escapes?
对 但是有一个地方不同
Yeah, with one important difference.
这不是假锁
This isn't a trick lock.
它被换成真锁
It's been switched for a real one.
真是杀人的好方法
What a way to kill someone.
他们是魔术师 法官大人
They're magicians, Your Honor.
表演者 他们利用普通事物掩盖残酷真相
Showmen, men who live by dressing up plain and sometimes brutal truths,
让人感到惊奇震撼
to amaze, to shock.
就算没有观众?
Even without an audience?
有一个观众
There was an audience.
这座水箱
You see, this water tank
对他们有特别的意义
was of particular significance to these two men.
很可怕的意义
Particularly awful significance.
谁有胆量上台绑住这位美女?
Which of you brave souls is willing to bind this lovely young woman?
绑住她的手腕
If you would tie her wrists,
还有她的腿和脚踝
bind her feet around the ankle.
- 你们是水手吗? - 不是
- Are either of you gentlemen sailors? - No.
我想你们应该都会打的很紧
I'm sure you can both tie a strong knot.
罗伯特!
Robert!
不 不
No, no.
茱莉亚 茱莉亚!
Julia. Julia!
我认识一名老水手
I knew an old sailor once.
他说他曾经落水
They told me he went overboard,
被船帆缠住
tangled in the sails.
他们救活了他
They pulled him out,
整整花了五分钟
but it took him five minutes to cough.
他说感觉就好像是...
He said it was like...
...回到家
...going home.
波登 你想干什么?
What do you want, Borden?
请你节哀顺变 安杰
I'm sorry for your loss, Angier.
你到底绑了什么结?
Which knot did you tie?
我一直问我自己这件事
I keep asking myself that.
- 结果呢? - 结果...
- And? - And...
抱歉 我...我真的不知道
I'm sorry, I just... don't know.
你不知道?
You don't know?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不知道?
You don't know?
你不知道?!
You don't know?!
- 艾佛? - 好消息 我们今天有表演了
- Alfred? - Good news. We got our first booking.
我们没见过面吧
I don't think we've had the pleasure.
- 法隆是我的机关师 - 你从哪里拿到这些...?
- Mr. Fallon is my engineer. - Where did you get all...?
- 求来的 借来的... 别问了 - 这位法隆先生
- I had to borrow and... don't ask. - He's a very enterprising soul
很有办法...
is... is Mr. Fallon. So...
- 我们没钱支付他 - 有观众就会有钱
- We can't afford to pay him. - The money will come with the audience.
那现在呢? 我赚的钱只够养活我们俩
But what about until then? What I earn, it's barely enough for us.
别担心 我的食物分他一半
Don't worry about it. I'll share half my food with him or something.
你得先分给另一个人
You're going to be doing that with someone else.
不会吧? 你...
No. You're...
我要生宝宝了
Having a baby.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我们应该告诉法隆 棒呆了 我们有孩子了
We should have told Fallon. That is great. We are having a baby.
过来
Oh, come here.
噢
Oh.
艾佛 这是什么?
Alfred, what is this?
这是用来吸引经纪人的戏法
Oh, this is just the trick to work Ackerman up at the end of my act.
这就是你所谓的伟大魔术?
Is it the masterpiece, the great trick?
不是 市场还不够成熟
No, no, no, the world is not ready for that one yet.
这只是一般的"接子弹"把戏
This is just your run-of-the-mill, daring, spectacular bullet catch.
- 接子弹 - 对 很安全
- A bullet catch. - Yeah, but it's safe.
我保证 你看
I promise. Look.
- 向我开枪 - 向你开枪?
- Shoot me. - Shoot you?
来吧 开枪
Go on, shoot me.
- 射这里 - 我办不到
- Right there. - No, I can't.
不是射那里 射我胸口...
No, no, not there. Shoot me here. Don't...
怎么样?
How's that?
太神了 你是怎么做到的
That's very good. Tell me how you do it.
我不能告诉你
No, I can't do that.
- 那你就不准表演 - 不准表演?
- Well, then you can't do it. - I can't do it?
对不起 我不能一个人养孩子
I'm sorry, but I can't raise a child on my own.
那你不能告诉任何人
You don't tell anybody that I told you.
- 好 - 火药
- OK. - Gunpowder.
填弹塞
Wadding.
子弹
Then the bullet.
推弹杆
Ramrod.
伸出你的手
Hold out your hand.
点燃火药时枪管并没有子弹
The bullet is not even in the gun when the charge is fired.
知道了就没什么了不起
Once you know, it's actually very obvious.
不过还是会...
Well, I mean, you still get...
还是很危险
It's dangerous.
- 会出人命的 - 怎么会?
- People still get killed doing that. - How?
有些笨蛋搞不好把铜板或是纽扣放进去
You get some smartass who could put a penny or a button
甚至把子弹放进去
or, God forbid, Sarah, somebody could put a bullet down there.
别担心 别担心
Don't worry. Don't worry,
我不会让任何意外发生
because I'm not gonna let anything happen.
一切都不会有事 因为...
Everything's gonna be all right because...
...我非常爱你
...I love you very much.
- 再说一次 - 我爱你
- Say it again. - I love you.
- 今天你不爱我 - 什么?
- Not today. - What?
有时你不真诚 今天你不是真心的
Well, some days it's not true, and today you don't mean it.
也许今天你比较爱魔术
Maybe today you're more in love with magic than me.
我能分辨个中的差别
I like being able to tell the difference.
如果真心说爱我
It makes the days it is true
今天就更有意义
mean something.
好吧
All right.
各位 这是钢圈
Metal rings, ladies and gentlemen.
现场有绅士淑女吗?
If there are any ladies and gentlemen here.
- 这是实心的 - 这表演我看过了
- Solid metal. - Seen that already.
神
手
教
授
是谁丢的?
Who threw that?
你们是想看这个 对吧?
This is what you came for, is it?
那么...
So...
...谁要当志愿者?
...who wants to volunteer?
- 我要! - 我!
- I do! - Me!
我
Me.
你够种吗 先生?
Are you man enough, sir?
是的
Yes.
你到底绑什么结?
Which knot did you tie, Borden?
我不知道
I don't know.
他要我回答 我说了实话
He came in to demand an answer, and I told him the truth.
我为了那件事天人交战
That I have fought with myself over that night,
一半的我发誓绑了简单的绳结
one half of me swearing blind that I tied a simple slipknot,
另一半的我记得我绑了蓝氏结
the other half convinced that I tied the Langford double.
我永远都无法确定
I can never know for sure.
他怎么会不知道!
How can he not know!
他怎么会不知道?
How can he not know?
他一定知道自己做了什么
He must know what he did.
一定的
He must.
莎拉 很痛耶
Sarah, that bloody hurts.
我不懂 怎么又流血了
I don't understand how it can be bleeding again.
根本就没有治好
It's as bad as the day it happened.
- 我去请大夫来 - 我们请不起大夫
- We have to get a doctor back. - We can't afford the doctor back.
- 你吵醒她了 - 太好了
- You've woken her. - Great.
对不起 伤口愈合了我才能回去表演
I'm sorry, I need this to heal so I can get back to work.
面对现实吧 伤成这样你还能表演?
You've got to face things. What tricks can you perform with this injury?
我能耍扑克牌 用道具表演
I can do car pulls. I can do some prop tricks.
我还是能表演我说的那个绝招
I can still do that. I can do the trick I've been telling you about.
千古留名的伟大表演
The one that they're gonna remember me for.
相信我
Come on.
没想到答案就在酒杯底下
I never thought I'd find an answer at the bottom of a pint glass.
你随时都在找答案
Hasn't stopped your looking.
听说有一场表演 不错的小戏院
Heard about a booking. Nice little theater.
- 魔术界的年轻新秀 - 要找谁?
- Young, up-and-coming magician. - Who?
- 你 - 我? 你替我找表演机会? 为什么?
- You. - Me? Booking? Why?
我想继续工作
I want to keep on working.
谁会雇用害死女助手的机关师?
Who's going to hire the engineer that killed Julia McCullough?
还是在满座的奥芬大剧院
in front of a sellout crowd at the Orpheum
那并不是你的错
Someone who knows it wasn't your fault.
波登绑错结 害死茱莉亚
Someone who knows Alfred Borden and his repertoire of exotic knots.
我听说他表演接子弹出了差错
I hear he had a spot of bad luck catching a bullet south of the river.
那一招本来就很危险
That's a dangerous trick, that one.
我们得把窗户刷白
We'll have to whitewash the windows,
不要让好奇的行人看进来
confound the more curious members of the public, but it will do.
- 我们先得找一名助手 - 我已经找到了
- We should see about an assistant. - I've made some arrangements.
你想好艺名了吗?
You settled on a name?
想好了
Yes, I have.
魔术大师丹顿
The Great Danton.
似乎有点老派?
It's a bit old-fashioned, isn't it?
不 这对我意义非凡
No, it's sophisticated.
大家都看过这招鸟笼魔术
The birdcage can't be our climax. Everybody knows it.
- 他们没看过这一招 - 我不想杀鸽子
- Not like this. - I don't want to kill doves.
那就别干这行
Then stay off the stage.
魔术师不是巫师
You're a magician, not a wizard.
你想成功 就得杀生
You got to get your hands dirty, if you're going to achieve the impossible.
这边请 温小姐
In here, Miss Wenscombe.
要是塞不进去你就白来了 站右边
No point in meeting Mr. Angier if you don't fit. On the right.
- 这有什么难? - 并不难
- What's so hard about this? - Nothing.
你要... 躺在下面
You're going... down here.
- 这样就能隐藏鸟笼? - 没错 当然
- And this will conceal, right? - Oh, sure.
- 好了吗? - 好了
- Tighten up on there. - Yep.
把这个别在下面
OK.
这绑在这里?
This ties up here?
- 这绑在前面 - 很好
- Ties in the back. - Good.
尽量憋住气
Breathe as little as possible.
看到没? 它会被压扁
Now, you see?
- 我懂了 - 好
- That's it. - OK.
她没经验
She's not experienced,
不过很会秀自己
but she knows how to present herself.
美丽的女助手最能转移注意力
A pretty assistant is the most effective form of misdirection.
谢谢大家 各位 最后的魔术表演
Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, for my final trick,
需要两名志愿者
I will require the assistance of two volunteers.
梅老板 麻烦你用手盖住好吗?
Mr. Merrit, if you would oblige me?
好的
Yep.
- 底下? - 对 地下
- Under? - Under, yeah.
绕住他的脚
Come around his foot.
- 小心点 - 他没问题
- Careful. - It's all right.
- 一名志愿者把手放这里 - 这样?
- Your volunteer, put their hand there. - Yeah?
另一名放在那里
And another one here.
梅老板 把手放在鸟笼的两侧
If you'll place your hands on either side of the cage, please.
谢谢你 奥莉薇雅
Thank you, Olivia.
你最好别伤害小动物 安杰
You best not be intending to hurt this animal, Mr. Angier.
- 当然不会 - 准备好了吗? 好的
- Of course not. - Ready? Right.
- 一... - 二...
- One... - Two...
三
Three.
太惊人了
That's bloody marvelous, Cutter.
太棒了
Very nice.
最棒的是...
And the best part is...
我以为我得杀生
I thought you said I had to get my hands dirty.
将来也许
Someday, perhaps you will.
我只想确定你行不行
I just had to know that you can.
很不错 真的很棒
Very nice. Very nice, indeed.
谢谢你 你的剧院也很棒
I haven't had the chance to compliment you on your beautiful theater.
坐满了观众会更棒
It'll be a lot more beautiful when it's full.
别担心
Don't worry.
你们都这么说 我才不担心
You all say that. Why should I worry
你不行我换人就是了
If your tricks don't get them in, somebody else's will.
或许有人愿意接子弹或水底脱逃?
Maybe somebody willing to do a bullet catch or a water escape?
那是洒狗血的技俩
Cheap thrills, Mr. Merrit.
大家只想看发生意外
People hoping for an accident, likely to see one too.
那对你的生意有什么好处?
What would that do for your business?
给你一个星期 约翰
You got a week, John.
谢谢你 梅老板
Thank you, Mr. Merrit.
仅此一周
伟大的丹顿
谢谢
Thank you.
呃... 那位先生 第三排
Uh... Sir, in the third row there.
请站起来让大家看你的手帕
Please stand up and show us your handkerchief.
这不是我的
This isn't mine.
请你把手帕还给第二排的女士
Perhaps you'd return it to the lady in the aisle of the second row.
我相信她有你的手帕
I believe she has yours.
抱歉 我一直出错 我好紧张
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm making so many mistakes. I'm so nervous.
观众好像没什么反应
The audience doesn't seem to be responding.
他们见多识广
They've seen a lot of tricks before,
但我保证下一个魔术他们从没看过
but not this next one.
拿一块布遮住
Cloth over.
祝我好运
Keep your fingers crossed.
我会准备香槟庆祝
I'll have the champagne ready.
- 你们看过这一招? - 老套了
- You've seen this one before? - We've seen them all before.
那我就让它更具挑战性 可以吗?
I'll make it a little harder then, shall I?
我要两位志愿者 一男一女
Two volunteers, please. A lady and a gentlemen.
跟我一起握住鸟笼
To hold this cage with me.
我要表演前所未有
I'll perform this feat in a manner
世界首创 无人见识过的全新魔术
never before seen by yourselves or any other audience anywhere in the world.
女士 一只手放后面
Madame, place one hand on the back of the cage,
另一只放前面
one hand on the front.
先生 一只手放底下
Sir, one hand on the bottom of the cage
另一只放上面
one hand on the top.
- 我早该认出他来 - 你忙着表演
- I should've spotted him. - You had a lot of plates going.
- 他们不会让我再秀这一招了 - 没错
- Don't suppose we can do this again. - No.
- 那要用哪一招当压轴? - 压轴?
- So, what's the climax of our show? - Show?
- 你没得表演了 - 梅老板 我们的合约是一星期
- You don't have a show. - We have a week's engagement.
我要你变魔术 不是杀小鸟或折断客人手指
To perform magic, not butcher birds and break my customers' fingers.
卷铺盖滚蛋 不然就全烧掉
Clear out, anything here in the morning gets burned.
- 梅老板... - 没得谈了 约翰
- Mr. Merrit... - It's done, John.
我找了个扫把星 你知道我最讨厌扫把星
I've hired a comedian. You know I hate comedians.
好吧 好剧院多得是
Well, there's plenty of good theaters.
我们找个新魔术
If we can come up with a new trick,
- 换个艺名 - 我不换艺名
- change the name of the act. - The name stays.
好吧 不过新魔术一定要很炫
Right, well, then the new trick's gonna have to be irresistible then.
我还有好几招可以试
I have a couple of methods to try out.
但要有新的表现方式
And then we need a new angle on the presentation.
如果你要找灵感
And if you need some inspiration,
皇家亚伯厅本周有个科技展
there's a technical exposition at the Albert Hall this week.
工程师 科学家都会去
Engineers, scientists, you know?
这些事物吸引大众的好奇心
That sort of thing captures the public's imagination.
我能坐这儿吗? 泰斯拉在暴风雨时派我来
Mind if I join you? Tesla sends me down here during the storms.
是陪丹顿大师喝一杯的好借口
Perfect excuse to come join the Great Danton for a drink.
来两杯
Two of them.
这雨下得真好 我好想念纽约
Beautiful, isn't it? God, I miss New York, though.
- 你来这里干嘛? - 这里有闪电
- Why are you here? - The lightning lives here.
而且人烟稀少
And not much else.
我们的工作是秘密
Our work is secret.
这是字谜吗?
That a cipher?
这本日记每天都换字母密码
A rotating transposition that shifts every day of the diary.
看似简单 就算有字母密码 解码也会花很多时间
Simple but time-consuming to translate, even with the five-letter keyword.
密码是什么?
Which is?
我们魔术师有道义要保密
We magicians have a circle of trust.
你偷别人的日记也叫道义?
You have a circle of trust with someone whose diary you stole?
搞不好我是用买的
Maybe I bought it.
你想从里面找出秘密?
And you're hoping to find a great secret in there?
我已经找到了
I've already found it.
所以才来这里
That's why I'm here.
泰斯拉替一名魔术师做了机关
Tesla built one for another magician.
你干嘛要同样的东西?
Why would you want the same thing?
这是同行间的较劲
Call it a professional rivalry.
泰斯拉专门帮怪人做古怪的机关
Mr. Tesla has built unusual machines for unusual people.
- 但我们不会说出去的 - 没问题
- But he would never talk about it. - I understand discretion.
我只想要那台机关
I just want the machine.
把酒干了
Finish your drink.
我带你去看样东西
I want to show you something. I think you'll have
你会很佩服我们的工作
a special appreciation for our work.
- 我以为那是秘密 - 你是魔术师
- I thought it was a secret. - You're a magician.
谁会相信你说的话?
Who's gonna believe you?
就快到了
Not long now.
我们的装备需要大量的电力
Our equipment requires a great deal of current.
泰斯拉替全镇提供电力
Tesla electrified the whole town
交换条件是使用发电机的权利
in exchange for using the generators when we need them.
我们趁镇民睡着时做实验
We do our tests when the townspeople are asleep.
泰斯拉不想吓到大家
Mr. Tesla doesn't want to scare anyone.
电线在哪里?
Where are the wires?
问得好
Exactly.
发电机呢?
Where's the generator?
就是你上星期看到的那台
You saw it last week.
- 那一定离这里有十英里 - 十五英里
- That must be ten miles from here. - Fifteen.
每天都要骑这么远才能回家睡觉
And I have to ride all of them before I get to bed.
过几天我会给你消息
I'll send word for you in a few days, Mr. Angier.
魔法 真正的魔法
Magic. Real magic.
这一切都只在皇家亚伯厅展出
Now appearing, only here at London's Royal Albert Hall,
科技奇迹
这个时代的奇迹
one of the miracles of our age.
科技的惊奇 你这辈子从来没看过
A technological marvel. You've never seen anything like it in your lives.
就算亲眼目睹也不敢相信
Your eyes will not believe what they're witnessing.
各位先生女士 泰斯拉的奇迹
The miracle of Nikola Tesla, ladies and gentlemen.
零污染的免费电力 你想看到未来吗?
Free, clean power. Like to know the future?
那个人将改变世界
The man who's speaking right now is going to change the world.
女士先生 快进来坐 位子很多 不用等
Come one, come all. Immediate seating, no waiting.
交流电奇迹
各位女士先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
有些观众有意见 担心安全的问题...
objections have been raised...
是应该有意见 你认为安全吗?
They should be raised. Does that look safe to you?
这是爱迪生的毁谤行动
Part of Thomas Edison's smear campaign
故意中伤泰斯拉的交流电研究
against Mr. Tesla's superior alternating current.
我们要求泰斯拉放弃展出
We have asked Mr. Tesla to reconsider.
但是他不会!
Which he will not!
不过他拒绝在受限情况下现身
But I've been told he refuses to appear under any such restrictions.
快走 这东西快爆炸了
This thing's gonna blow.
拜托大家别紧张
Ladies and gentlemen, please.
嗨
Hey.
嗨 洁丝
Hello, Jess.
你今天跟妈妈过得好吗?
Have you had a nice day with mommy? Huh?
莎拉
Sarah.
- 我爱你 - 你今天是真心说爱我
- I love you. - See, today it's true.
- 是的 - 哈
- Yeah. - Hello.
我看见了幸福
I saw happiness.
应该属于我的幸福
Happiness that should have been mine.
但是我错了
But I was wrong.
笔记中透露 他没有我所羡慕的生活
His notebook reveals that he never had the life that I envied.
前一刻他渴望的家庭生活
The family life that he craves one minute,
下一刻就想反抗 追求自由
he rails against the next, demanding freedom.
他的精神... 精神分裂
His mind... his mind is a divided one.
心灵无法平静
His soul is restless.
他的妻女
His wife and child, tormented
被他易变和矛盾的天性折磨着
by his fickle and contradictory nature.
你要叫洋娃娃什么名字?
So, what do you think you'll call her?
不知道
I don't know.
大家都有名字啊 她呢?
Everybody needs a name, so, what's hers?
那就叫莎拉吧
Maybe Sarah.
很美的名字 很美的名字
That's a lovely name. That's a lovely name.
你们聊聊今天想做的事
Well, you talk about what you want to do for the rest of the day.
去跟她说吧
All right, go on, you talk with her.
他们要把她带走?
Are they taking her away?
送到童工工厂?
To the workhouse?
来 你们继续说话
You keep talking.
告诉欧文我答应了 拿去吧
Tell Owens I've reconsidered. Take it.
拿去吧
Go on, take it.
这样对大家最好
It's for the best.
给我看
Let me see.
我要学会教授你所有的绝招
I'm gonna learn all the professor's secrets.
我得先教你识字
Only if I teach you how to read.
这些魔术没有屁用 不是吗?
They're just stupid tricks, right?
完全不能帮你逃出去 不是吗?
Haven't helped you get out of here, have they?
教授 你能解开真的锁吗?
Or can't you undo real locks, professor?
也许我只是在等待时机
Maybe I'm just biding my time.
有一天我会...
Maybe one day I'll...
...张开双手请你看
...open my hand, get your attention,
然后问 "你在注意看吗?"
ask, "Are you watching closely?"
也许念一 两句咒语
Maybe a magic whirl or two.
然后我就消失不见
And then I'll be gone.
你凭什么这么出名?
How'd you get so famous then?
魔术
Magic.
波登! 给我回来!
Oi! Borden, get back here!
多谢啦
Thank you.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
谁有钥匙?!
Where's the bloody key?!
1899年2月8日
February 8, 1899.
今天终于有了突破
Today, finally, a breakthrough.
泰斯拉同意见我
Tesla's agreed to see me.
这百分之百安全
Perfectly safe.
你是魔术大师丹顿
So this is the Great Danton.
艾利经常说你的表演很精彩
Mr. Alley has effused about your act to me on any number of occasions.
伸出另一只手
Hold out other hand.
- 电流从哪里通过? - 我们的身体 安先生
- What's conducting the electricity? - Our bodies, Mr. Angier.
我们的身体能生产 并制造能源
Quite capable of conducting and, indeed, producing energy.
你吃过了吗 安先生?
Have you eaten, Mr. Angier?
我需要惊世骇俗的魔术
I need something impossible.
你听过这句俗话吗 "心有余而力不足"?
You're familiar with the phrase, "Man's reach exceeds his grasp"?
那不是真话
Is a lie.
人类只是胆量不够
Man's grasp exceeds his nerve.
社会一次只能接受一种改变
Society only tolerates one change at a time.
我第一次试着改变世界
First time I tried to change the world,
被称为先知
I was hailed as a visionary.
第二次...
Second time...
...他们却请我退休
...I was asked politely to retire.
所以我在这里享受退休时光
So here I am, enjoying my retirement.
没有不可能的事 安先生 只是你想要的东西耗资巨大
Nothing is impossible, Mr. Angier. What you want is simply expensive.
你准备只用这机器
If I were to build for you this machine,
来表演魔术?
you would be presenting it merely as illusion?
如果大家把我的表演当真
Well, if people actually believed the things I did on stage,
就不会鼓掌 只会尖叫
they wouldn't clap, they'd scream.
想想看 把女人锯成两半
Think of sawing a woman in half.
你想过这机器的代价吗?
Have you considered the cost of this?
钱不是问题
Price is not an object.
或许吧 你有想过代价吗?
Perhaps not, but have you considered the cost?
我不懂你的意思
I'm not sure I follow.
回家吧 忘了这件事
Go home, forget this thing.
我看得出你着了魔
I can recognize an obsession.
- 这不会有好事 - 你自己着了魔也没好事吗?
- No good will come of it. - Hasn't good come of your obsessions?
一开始有 但我沉迷太久了
At first, but I have followed them too long.
我成了它的奴隶
I am their slave.
总有一天 它们会毁了我
And one day, they will choose to destroy me.
既然着了魔 那你就该知道我不会改变心意
If you understand an obsession, then you know you won't change my mind.
就这样吧
So be it.
你愿意打造了吗?
Will you build it?
我已经开始打造了 安先生
I've already begun to build it, Mr. Angier.
希望你享受山上的空气 这得花点时间
I hope you enjoy the mountain air. This will take some time.
教\h\h\h\h\h授
超越了死亡
带着全新的魔术华丽回归
瞬间\h\h\h\h\h\h\h转移
伦敦城内最精彩纷呈
为人称道的演出
呃... 我以为你走了
Uh... I thought you'd gone.
我没有地方可以去
I don't really have anywhere to go.
你都睡在这里?
You've been sleeping here?
柯特说我可以睡在这里 你在做什么?
Cutter said it'd be all right till we get another booking. What are you doing?
呃... 做研究
Uh... research.
魔术师的一部分工作
Part of a magician's job
就是... 刺探对手表演什么...
is to... watch his competition, see what illusions...
你打算对付他 对吧?
You're going to do something to that man, aren't you?
柯特希望你忘了这件事
Cutter's hoping you let things lie.
如果波登觉得你们扯平了...
He says if Borden thinks things are even between you...
扯平?
Even?
他用手指换我太太的命?
My wife for a couple of his fingers?
他现在有家有室又能上台表演
He has a family now and he's performing again.
波登继续过着日子
Borden is out there living his life just as he intended,
假装没事发生 看看我
as if nothing had happened and look at me.
我孤家寡人 没戏院要请我表演
I'm alone and no theater will touch me.
是我们
Us.
你需要更好的伪装
You're going to need a better disguise.
我需要志愿者
I need a volunteer.
发生什么事?
What happened?
你伤了他吗?
Did you hurt him?
怎么了 罗伯特?
What happened, Robert?
你 先生 这只是个皮球 对吧?
You, sir. Just a rubber ball, yes?
谢谢
Thank you.
只是个皮球? 不
Just a rubber ball? No.
但它一点也不普通
Not normal. Not a normal rubber ball.
它有魔力
It's magic.
波登有个新魔术
He had a new trick.
很棒吗?
Was it good?
那是我看过最棒的魔术戏法
It was the greatest magic trick I've ever seen.
观众有没有鼓掌?
Did they applaud when you saw it?
戏法太棒 太简单了 观众根本来不及看得懂
It was too good. It was too simple. The audience hardly had time to see it.
- 他是个糟糕的魔术师 - 不 他是很厉害的魔术师
- He's a dreadful magician. - No, he is a wonderful magician.
只是一个糟糕的表演者 完全不懂得包装
He's a dreadful showman. He doesn't dress it up,
- 宣传他的魔术 - 那他到底怎么变的?
- how to sell it. - How does he do it?
- 他使用替身 - 不 这太简单了
- He uses a double. - No, it's too simple.
一定更复杂
This is a complex illusion.
你不知道窍门才会这么说
You say that because you don't know the method.
后来现身的是替身 就是这样
It's a double that comes out. It's the only way.
我看过三次 是同一个人
I've seen him perform it three times. The prestige is the same man.
- 不 不是 - 从第二道门出来的是同一人
- No, it's not. - The same man comes out of the cabinet.
是同一个人
It's the same man.
他戴着手套掩饰断指
He wears padded gloves to hide his damaged fingers,
仔细看就看得出来
but, if you look closely, you can tell.
他不会吸引观众 但是我会
He doesn't know how to sell it to an audience, but I do.
我们可以用来当压轴表演
Yeah, we could use it as a climax to the show.
没错
Yes.
他毁了我一生 我就偷他的戏法
The man stole my life, I'm gonna steal his trick.
我们要找个很像你的人
We got to find someone who looks like you.
- 他没有用替身 - 罗伯特 我不知道波登的手法
- He doesn't use a double. - I don't know how Borden does it.
你要不... 要不就等他退休向他买秘诀
Either... You either wait for him to retire and buy the secret,
或是听我解释要怎么表演
or you listen to how I would do it.
我知道唯一的手段
And the only way that I know how to do it
就是用替身
is to find you a bloody good double.
好吧
All right.
看清楚我的样子 去找我吧
Take a good look. Let's get out there and find me.
哇!
Whoo!
你看 你看
Look, look.
这是什么?
What's that?
- 这是给你的 - 用来做什么呢?
- It's for you. - What's this for?
过来
Come.
你...
You...
- 我上礼拜问过你... - 那时候我心情不好
- I asked you last week... - You caught me in a wrong mood.
- 但是你一直反对... - 莎拉
- But you won't ever... - Sarah,
我可以改变主意吧?
I'm gonna have to change my mind, aren't I?
我的表演很成功 换一家大剧院表演 就能赚大钱
The act is taking off. Soon we'll be in a bigger theater, things will work out.
我不敢相信 谢谢你 谢谢你 好美喔
I can't believe it. Thank you. Thank you. It's beautiful.
- 杰瑞? - 亲爱的 看看你
- Gerry? - Darling, look at you.
两位 这是杰瑞路特
Mr. Cutter, Mr. Angier, I'd like you to meet Gerald Root.
嗯
Mm-hm.
幸会了 很荣幸认识你们
A pleasure. Pleasure to meet you fine gentlemen.
你想听我说笑话吗? 过来
Would you like for me to tell you a little joke? Come here.
怎样 你在笑吗?
Yes. Are you laughing now?
我得去尿尿
I have to take a piss.
- 他是个疯汉 - 当然了 他是个失业演员
- He's out of his mind. - Of course, he's an out-of-work actor.
他很好 外表修饰一下
He's perfect. He needs a little help.
经我处理好了后 就能当你的兄弟
But when I get done with him, he could be your brother.
我不要他当我兄弟 而是变成我
I don't need him to be my brother, I need him to be me.
给我一个月的时间
Give me a month.
你打开门...
So you open the door...
...然后...
...and...
跳下来吧
Come on.
你就不能找个软垫子吗?
Couldn't you have found a softer one?
这又不是睡觉用的
Well, it's not for sleeping on.
你从那上面跳下来...
So, if you come down through there...
- ...路特就从那边上去吗? - 没错
- ...does Root go up through there? - Yep.
这会令人叹为观止
It's going to be amazing.
一定要 波登的魔术大受欢迎
Well, it has to be. Borden's trick is getting noticed.
今天已经客满了
The place was packed today.
你又去看他的表演
You went and saw his show again.
准备见你自己吗 安先生?
Ready to meet yourself, Mr. Angier?
我只要喝得烂醉
All I have to do is keep myself stinking drunk,
就不会被识破
and no one will be able to tell the difference.
你要有点信心
Have a little faith, sir.
路先生 麻烦你表演行吧?
Now, would you favor us with a performance, Mr. Root?
你若像我看尽人情冷暖 也会借酒浇愁
You'd drink, too, if you knew the world half as well as I do.
你以为你很特别吗?
Did you think you were unique?
我扮演过凯撒跟浮士德
I've been Caesar, I've played Faust.
扮你这丹顿大师能有多难?
How difficult could it possibly be to play the Great Danton?
你可以变回自己了 不然开除你
You can go back to being yourself now, Root, for nothing.
我宁愿变成他
I'd rather be him for now.
我发现这还... 蛮好玩的
I find it, uh... amusing.
"陛下
"My liege,
莎士比亚中的台词
我并没有拒交战俘"
I did deny no prisoners."
- 你扮得好像哦 - 谢了
- You look wonderful. - Oh, thank you.
路特必须保持低调 被人看到我们就玩完了
Root has to keep a low profile. Anyone sees him, the game's up.
我不知道你的做法 我也不想知道
I don't know how you do things. I'm not sure I wanna know.
你决定这魔术叫什么吗?
Have you thought what we should call it a trick?
没必要遮遮掩掩 波登称他的表演为"移形遁影术"
There's no point being coy. Borden calls his trick The Transported Man.
新瞬间转移
各位 你们今晚看到的
Ladies and gentlemen, much of what you've seen may be termed
多半都是魔术或是小把戏
as illusions or entertaining trifles.
但是...
Alas...
...下一个表演并不是魔术
...I cannot claim this next feat as illusion.
仔细看
Watch carefully.
绝对看不到机关
You will see no trickery,
因为这是真的
for no trickery is employed.
只有遥远东方的奇人异士
Merely a technique familiar to certain citizens of the Orient
以及喜马拉雅山的圣者才会
and various holy men of the Himalayas.
的确 有些观众看过这个表演
Indeed, many of you may be familiar with this technique,
没看过的请不要紧张
but for those of you who are not, do not be alarmed.
这个表演绝对安全
What you're about to see is considered safe.
敬我们的成功
To our achievement.
经理说他没看过这么热烈的反应
The manager says he's never seen a reaction like it.
至少他看到了 我只能躲在台下
At least he saw it. I spent the ovation hiding under the stage.
观众才懒得管消失的人
No one cares about the man who disappears.
他们只在乎现身的大师
They care about the one who comes out on the other side.
我就关心消失的人
I care about the man in the box.
谢谢你 也许我们能换过来
Thank you. I don't know, maybe we could switch before the trick.
由我来现身 让路特跳到舞台底下
I'm the prestige, and Root's below stage.
不行 观众的期望最重要
No, the anticipation of the trick is everything.
你的舞台魅力才能营造张力
We need your showmanship to build up the suspense.
他一开口就完了 没办法表演
Once Root opens his mouth, it's over. He can't introduce this trick.
我当然行 我是丹顿大师
Of course I can. I'm the Great Danton.
路特 你这猪头 把这身装扮脱掉
Root, you bloody fool, get out of that wardrobe and makeup.
随时都可能有人经过
Anyone could walk in here at any minute.
恭喜了 各位
Congratulations, all.
成功不是偶然的 我们很努力
Life is not full of these moments. We worked hard.
我们要好好庆祝
We need to celebrate properly.
怎么了? 想起你太太?
What's wrong? Is it your wife?
不是 这魔术还不够好
No, it's the trick. It isn't good enough.
波登比不上我们 他没有格调
Borden's trick is nothing compared to ours. He has no style.
他最后不必躲在舞台底下
He doesn't spend the finale hiding under the stage.
- 我要知道他的做法 - 为什么?
- I need to know how he does it. - Why?
这样我就可以做得更好
So I can do it better.
我要你去当他的助手
I need you to go and work for him.
当他助手? 你在开玩笑?
Work for him? Are you joking?
你得当我的间谍
You'll be my spy.
我们才刚成功 你就要我走?
We just got our start. You want me to leave?
这样才能进步 想想看
That's how we advance. Think of it.
柯特的技俩已经让观众兴奋了 试想一下
People are excited by Cutter's version. Imagine what we'd do
我们用正版魔术岂不更受欢迎 这将是前所未见的伟大魔术
with the real illusion. We'd have the greatest magic act anyone's ever seen.
- 他知道我是你的助手 - 正因为如此他才会雇佣你
- He knows I work for you. - Exactly why he'll want to hire you.
- 他会用你来打探我的秘诀 - 他凭什么信任我?
- He'll want my secret. - Why would he trust me?
因为你要告诉他真相
Because you're gonna tell him the truth.
嗯?
Hmm?
乖女孩
Good girl.
你一定想知道 花大钱买到的是什么
You must be curious to see what so much money has bought you.
你正好来目睹我们的处女秀
Fitting you should be here for her maiden voyage.
你的高帽
Your hat.
你最好退后一点
You might want to stand back.
我不明白
I don't understand.
让我们来处理就好了
Perhaps it would be best if you left us to it.
有问题吗 泰斯拉?
Is there a problem, Mr. Tesla?
- 没有 下星期再回来 - 下星期?
- No. Come back next week. - Next week?
- 下星期就没问题 - 泰斯拉!
- Next week, it will be fine. - Tesla!
机器有时候也会闹脾气
Just a little temperamental.
- 很不错的工作室 - 我们尽力了
- Interesting workshop. - Yeah, we make do.
- 我是奥莉薇雅... - 我知道你是谁
- My name is Olivia... - I know who you are.
你来偷我的秘诀?
Here to steal the rest of my show?
我有你缺少的东西
To give your show what it's missing.
- 我缺少什么? - 我
- Yeah, what might that be? - Me.
我刚才正在说这个 不是吗?
I was just saying that, wasn't I?
- 我们需要女性魅力 - 我离开安杰
- A woman's touch. - I've left Angier.
- 好的 - 我需要工作
- All right. - I want a job.
嗯
Yeah.
我知道你一定不信任我
I know you've no reason to trust me.
我为什么不信任你?
Why wouldn't I trust you?
你是我敌手的情人 怎么不能信任?
You're only the mistress of my enemy. Why wouldn't I trust you?
- 波登先生 - 艾佛
- Mr. Borden. - Alfred.
我要告诉你事实
I'm going to tell you the truth.
干我们这行
Now that is a slippery notion
没有所谓的事实 不是吗 温小姐?
in our line of work, isn't it, Miss Wenscombe?
我会来这里 是安杰派我来的
I am here because he sent me here.
他要我替你工作 偷你的秘诀
He wants me to work for you and steal your secret.
为什么? 他的魔术算顶尖了
What does he need my secret for? His trick is topnotch.
他消失后立刻出现在
He vanishes, and then he reappears instantly
舞台另一边 痴肥又不开口
on the other side of the stage, mute, overweight
而且喝得烂醉
and, unless I'm mistaken, very drunk.
不过还是很棒 何必偷我的? 告诉我 奥莉薇雅
It's astonishing. How does he do it? And tell me, Olivia,
他喜欢躲在台下吗?
does he enjoy taking his bows under the stage?
他快抓狂了 他像着了魔似的 只想知道你的手法
It's killing him. He's obsessed with discovering your methods.
表演成功还不满足
He thinks of nothing else, takes no pleasure in our success.
我受够了
And I've had enough.
跟他在一起没有未来
There is no future with him.
他派我来偷你的秘诀 但我来告诉你他的秘密
He sent me here to steal your secrets, but I've come to offer you his.
这是实话吗?
This is the truth... is it?
你赶快把衣服穿好
Think you'd better get dressed, sir.
路特 你迟到了 而且比平常更醉 立刻给我躲进舞台下面
Root, you're late and more drunk than usual. Get down below stairs right away.
不
No.
不 我们得聊一聊 柯特先生
No, we need to have a little chat, Mr. Cutter.
麻烦大了 波登就在对街表演
We have a problem. Cutter, Borden is performing right across the street.
这里的问题更大
Yeah, we have a bigger problem.
路特 他发现他可以狮子大开口
Root. He's realized that he can make demands.
什...? 他要勒索我们?
Wha...? He's blackmailing us?
我倒是很惊讶 说实话
I was surprised, to tell you the truth.
这种人通常过很久才会想通
It usually takes them a lot longer to figure it out.
- 他要多少? - 这无关紧要
- How much does he want? - It makes no difference.
- 我们得暂停演出 - 暂停演出? 你看看
- We've got to stop doing the trick. - Stop the trick? Look at this.
你看看上礼拜的报纸 他们说你是伦敦首席表演家
Last week they said you were the premier stage performer in London.
班狄斯剧院
下周起为您呈现
教\h\h\h\h授
原版瞬间转移
我们拒绝接受廉价的模仿
不是魔术师 而是表演家
Not magician, mind you. Performer of any kind.
- 你想说什么? - 我想说的是 你成名太快
- What's your point? - My point is, you've climbed too high
不能出纰漏
to get away with professional embarrassment.
最好别表演无法掌控的魔术
We don't do any tricks we can't control.
他想要多少都给他 继续表演 直到波登开幕
Just pay him whatever he wants for now. We keep doing the trick until Borden opens,
我们再喊停
and then we'll phase it out.
好吧
All right.
柯特很惊讶
Cutter was always surprised
路特这么快就造反
how fast Root turned bad.
我何德何能被你请喝啤酒?
To what do I owe the pleasure of this rather welcome pint of ale?
- 你是丹顿大师 对吧? - 嘘 嘘
- You're the Great Danton, aren't you? - Sh, sh, sh, sh, sh.
当然 别声张 我怕被骚扰
Of course I am, but don't advertise it, because I'll be mobbed with fans.
我们给他钱喝酒
We paid him enough to keep him in beers.
以防他扯后腿
You wouldn't expect him to rock the boat.
各位可能看过这个魔术
Many of you may be familiar with this technique,
没看过的人不要紧张
but for those of you who aren't, do not be alarmed.
这个魔术很安全
What you're about to see is considered safe.
- 你是谁? - 我是个仰慕者
- And who are you? - I am a humble admirer
也是魔术师
and a fellow practitioner.
非常好
Mmm. Very good.
- 再来一杯? - 如果你硬要请客
- Another one? - Oh, if you insist.
- 再来一杯 - 我今晚没有演出
- Another. - I'm not performing tonight.
我只负责表演 坦白说
I'm only doing one show, but to be frank,
一切都由其他人安排
my people pretty much run things these days.
给我上去
Get up there.
上去!
Get up!
你的移形遁影术
Your illusion, The Transported Man,
我并不知道个中秘密
I'm not claiming to know your methods,
但是我以前也有类似的表演
but I had a similar trick in my act,
而且... 我用一个替身
and, uh... I used a double.
- 我懂了 很好 - 结果出了麻烦
- Mm, I see, very good. - Well, it was, and then it went bad.
我没料到替身竟然
What I didn't count on was that when I incorporated this bloke
喧宾夺主
into my act,
把我的光彩全部夺走
he had complete power over me.
完全夺走?
Complete power, you say?
噢!
Ohh!
千万别让别人夺走你的光彩
Be very careful giving someone that power over you.
呃 谢谢你...
Huh. Thank you. Um...
谢谢你的忠告
Yes, thank you for the warning.
干杯
Hmm. Cheers.
下一个表演并不是魔术
I cannot claim this next feat as illusion.
不过这个表演很安全
What you're about to see is considered safe.
啊!
Ahh!
噢! 伟大的丹顿大师
Oh! The Great Danton.
班狄斯剧院开场演出
教授
我在此致歉
I apologize.
我在对街的表演太精彩...
There simply is too much magic...
...不小心把自己
...for my stage at The Pantages
变到这里来
across the street.
抱歉打扰了
Pardon my intrusion.
放过他吧 他已经很努力了
And go easy on the poor chap. He does try so very hard.
我不知道波登怎么找到他的
I don't know how Borden found him.
我很小心把他藏好
Kept him under wraps. I was careful.
还是被他找到了
Yeah, well, he did.
是她泄的密吗?
Do you think it was her?
你没料到是我吧?
You weren't expecting me?
你来晚了 你明明约下午
I expected you sooner. Your message said afternoon.
最近我的行动不便
It takes a bit for me to get around these days.
他从我身边夺走一切 妻子 事业
He's taken everything from me. My wife, my career,
- 还有你 - 是你派我来的
- now you. - You sent me.
我派你 是要你偷他的秘诀 不是帮助他
I sent you to steal his secret, not to improve his act.
- 那是我的工作 - 或是爱上他!
- It's my job. - Or fall in love!
- 我全都照你的话去做了! - 是吗?
- I did everything you asked! - Yes? Yes?
- 他到底用什么手法? - 柯特说的对 他用替身
- How does he do it? - Cutter was right, a double.
- 波登当然这么说 - 他什么都没说
- 'Course he said that. - He didn't say it.
我看到化妆 眼镜 假发 我们没用到
I've seen things, makeup, glasses, wigs. We don't use for the show.
- 不过都藏在后台 - 这是误导
- I've seen it hidden backstage. - It is misdirection.
他故意留下这些东西让你误以为他用替身
He leaves them lying around to make you think that.
难道他随时随地提放我吗 不可能
He doesn't know when I'm looking.
随时随地! 他就是这种人!
All the time, Olivia! That's who he is!
这就是生存必备法则!
That's what it takes!
他一直在演戏 你不懂吗?
He lives his act, don't you see?
他跟你上床不代表他信任你
Just because you're sleeping with him doesn't mean he trusts you.
你以为你什么都知道?
You think you can see everything, don't you?
丹顿大师是睁眼瞎子
The Great Danton is a blind fool.
这是他的笔记
His notebook.
你偷的?
You stole it?
借来的 只有今晚
I borrowed it for tonight.
我想你可以翻译...
I thought you could translate some of it...
不行 没人能翻译 这是字谜
I can't. No one can. It's a cipher.
就算有关键字 也得花几个月
Even with the keyword, it will take months to decode.
- 没有关键字呢? - 那就没辙了
- And without the keyword? - Perhaps never.
- 等着瞧吧 - 不能等了
- We'll see. - We will not see.
我明早不放回去 他就知道是我偷的
If I don't get that back by tomorrow he'll know I took it.
- 离开他 - 不行 他知道我住哪里
- Leave him. - I can't. He knows where I live.
这是他的日记 他的秘密都掌握在我手里
This is his diary, Olivia. All of his secrets are right here in my hands.
这不能让你妻子复生
It won't bring your wife back.
我才不在乎 我只要他的秘密
I don't care about my wife. I care about his secret.
听着...
Look, I'll, um...
我去他的工作室布置成入室抢劫
I'll go to his workshop and stage a break-in.
- 他会知道是你拿走的 - 对 是我 不是你
- He'll know you took it. - Yes, me. Not you.
懂吗?
Understand?
罗伯特
Robert.
我已经爱上他了
I have fallen in love with him.
那我就知道你有多为难了
Then I know how hard this has been for you.
他偷了笔记?
Notebook?
他不会就此罢手
Then he's just getting started.
班
狄
斯
教授
原版瞬间转移
教授!
Professor!
晚安
Good evening.
我今晚走路回家
I'm walking tonight.
让他来吧 我不在乎
Let him come. I don't care.
教授! 教授!
Professor! Professor!
啊哇!
Ahh!
- 你没事吧? - 死不了
- You all right? - I'm alive.
这样就省得我开个通风孔
Saves me cutting you an air hole.
- 我很佩服你 - 为什么?
- I'm impressed. - Why is that?
你终于动手杀生了
You're finally getting your hands dirty.
这就是伟大魔术的代价
It's what a good trick costs, Angier.
冒险 牺牲
Risk, sacrifice.
不给我我要的
The sacrifice, I'm afraid, is all gonna be yours,
只有你会被牺牲
unless you give me what I want.
- 你要什么? - 你的秘密
- Which is? - Your secret.
我的秘密?
My secret?
移形遁影术的手法
Your method for The Transported Man.
法隆不肯说 他根本不会说话
Fallon wouldn't tell me. He doesn't talk at all.
- 你拿到我的笔记 - 少了关键字也没用
- You have my notebook. - Useless without the keyword.
写出你的手法 详细写出来
Write down your method, Mr. Borden, describe it in full.
我要你的手法 不只是关键字
I want the whole method, not the keyword.
你的笔记也许根本没记载
I don't know if your secret's in your notebook.
关键字就是我的手法
The keyword is the method.
我的机关师呢?
Where's my engineer?
- 他还活着吗? - 看你能挖多快
- Alive? - How fast can you dig?
法隆 听得见吗? 法隆!
Fallon, you hear me? Fallon!
- 你的手臂怎样? - 幸好还在
- How's the arm? - Still attached.
找到你的答案了吗?
Did you find your answer?
我们的答案 我还没看 我们一起看
Our answer, Cutter. I haven't looked yet. I wanted you to share this.
我已经知道他是怎么变的
I already know how he does it, Robert.
他一贯的手法 跟我们一样
Same way he always has, the same way as we do.
但是你却不死心
It's just that you want something more.
我们一起看吧 好吗?
Well, let's find out then, shall we?
这是什么意思?
What does it mean?
即Nikola Tesla 交流电发明者
意思就是 我们得去旅行
It means, Cutter, we have a journey ahead of us.
- 到美国 - 罗伯特
- To America. - Robert?
听我说
Listen to me.
着魔是年轻人玩的游戏
Obsession is a young man's game.
别这么说
Come on.
我没办法再帮你了
I can't follow you any further in it.
不行了 很抱歉
I can't, I'm sorry.
我只好一个人去了
Then the rest is up to me.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
晚安 你好 亲爱的
Good evening. Hello, darling.
来瓶最好的香槟
Champagne, your finest.
我不知道会有客人
I didn't know we were going to be joined for dinner.
当然 大家要好好庆祝
Absolutely, we are celebrating.
温小姐 法隆先生
Miss Wenscombe, Mr. Fallon.
- 我们要庆祝什么? - 我们有新的魔术
- What are we celebrating? - We've hit upon a new trick.
- 对吧? - 佛迪 什么魔术?
- Haven't we? - What trick, Freddie?
是啊 佛迪 什么魔术?
Yes, Freddie, what trick?
我每天晚上要把自己活埋
I am going to bury myself alive every night,
然后找人来把我挖出来
and then someone will come along and dig me up. Wonderful.
- 我老公酒喝多了... - 倒香槟 来吧
- I think my husband's had quite enough... - No, pour the champagne.
倒... 莎拉 少这样对我说话 别把我当三岁小孩
Pour the... Sarah, don't talk to me like that. I'm not a bloody child.
- 我最好先走... - 法隆 请送温小姐回家
- Perhaps it would be better... - Mr. Fallon, escort her home.
- 我老公很没礼貌 - 算了吧
- My husband's being a bore. - Oh, please.
- 何必让你们受罪 - 别这么扫兴嘛
- I see no reason you should suffer. - Don't ruin this evening.
晚安 波登夫人 晚安 佛迪
Good night, Mrs. Borden. Good night, Freddie.
- 佛迪? - 那是我的名字
- Freddie? - That's my name.
- 在家里不是 - 我又不常在家 对吧?
- Not at home. - I'm not always at home, am I?
你至少可以卸掉假胡子吧?
Couldn't you have at least taken off the beard?
莎拉 我才刚表演完
Sarah, I just came from the bloody theater just now.
好吗? 大家都喜欢我这个模样 大家都喜欢
All right? I'm out in public. Everybody else loves it.
你怎么会变成这样?
Why are you being like this?
我今天真的很不顺
I had a terrible ordeal today.
差点失去一件...
I thought that something very precious...
...很宝贵的东西
...had been lost to me.
我只想稍微庆祝一下
So I just wanted to celebrate just a little.
什么? 你失去什么?
All right, what? What did you lose?
我知道了 又是更多的秘密
I see, more secrets.
莎拉 秘密是我的生活重心
Sarah, secrets are my life.
- 我们的生活 - 艾佛 别再演了 这不是你
- Our life. - No, Alfred, stop, this isn't you.
别再演了
Stop performing.
我以为我是唯一的客人
I thought I had the place to myself.
有个不速之客 很没礼貌
Unexpected guests, not very polite.
问一大堆问题
A lot of questions.
一开始我以为他们替政府工作
At first, I thought they worked for the government.
- 不是吗? - 更糟 他们是爱迪生的手下
- No? - Worse, they work for Thomas Edison.
今天有不寻常的发展
Today, a most curious development.
他的女助手来找我
His assistant came to us with a proposition.
很明显 安杰派她来 承认自己是卧底
Obviously, Angier has sent her and told her to admit as much.
他喜欢躲在台下吗?
Does he enjoy taking his bows under the stage?
他派我来偷你秘诀 我来告诉你他的秘密
He sent me here to steal your secrets, but I've come to offer you his.
这是实话...
This is the truth...
...是吗?
...is it?
不 这是他叫我说的 其实...
No, that's what he told me to tell you. The truth...
...我是爱他的 一直在帮他
...is that I loved him and I stood by him and he sent me to you,
但是他把我当跑腿小妹派我来
like he would send a stagehand to pick up his shirts.
我恨他这样对我
I hate him for that.
我从大老远就看出安杰的手法
I could spot Angier's methods from the back of the theater.
那么你能给我什么?
So, what could you possibly have to offer me?
你或许知道他的手法
You may know his tricks,
但是你不懂 大家看不出你比较厉害
but you can't understand why no one sees yours are better.
你把断指包起来 我要很仔细看
You hide this. I had to look very closely
才看得出来
to spot it during The Transported Man,
不过这是你的优势
but this makes you unique.
这代表你没有用替身
It shows you aren't using a double.
别把手包起来 要大方秀出来
You mustn't hide it. You must display it proudly.
你只用一只手变魔术一定很厉害
I'm sure it takes great skill to perform illusions with one good hand.
对 没错
Yeah, it does.
你要让大家知道
So let people know.
你比他高杆 我可以教你怎么成名
You can be so much more than he is and I can show you how.
我想她说的是真话
I think she's telling the truth.
不过我们不能信任她
I think we cannot trust her.
但是我爱她 也需要她
But I love her. I need her.
打开心房接受这段感情
To open myself to such a relationship,
面对外遇的危险
to the dangers of such an affair,
我必须确认她对我忠贞不二
I need assurances of fidelity, of love.
该怎么确信呢?
But how to be sure?
我有个方法 那是了解她心意的唯一方法
I know a way. It's the only way to know her mind.
他怎么舍得让你离开?
How could he send you away?
她必须帮我们除掉安杰
She must help me rid ourselves of Angier.
今天我的情妇证明了她的真心
Today, my mistress proves her truthfulness.
不是向我证明
Not to me, you understand.
她带我去找路特时 我就相信她了
I've been convinced since she led me to Root.
今天她证明她爱我
Today, Olivia proves her love for me
在你面前 安杰
to you, Angier.
没错 安杰 是我要她把笔记交给你
Yes, Angier, she gave you this notebook at my request.
是的 "泰斯拉"只是关键字
And yes, "Tesla" is merely the key to my dairy,
不是秘诀 你真以为我会
not to my trick. You really think I'd part
那么轻易把秘诀给你?
with my secret so easily after so much?
再见 安杰
Goodbye, Angier.
祝你在美国的新家
May you find solace for your forward ambition
找到安慰
back in your American home.
泰斯拉!
Tesla!
泰斯拉! 艾利!
Tesla! Alley!
艾利!
Alley!
泰斯拉根本没打造我要的机器
Tesla never made a machine like the one I asked for.
- 我们没说他有啊 - 但你让我认为他有
- I never said he had. - You let me believe that he had.
你们资金用完 所以骗我的钱
You stole my money because your funding was cut off.
拿我的高帽做实验
You've been shooting sparks in my top hat,
一边嘲笑我 一边拿我的钱来花
laughing at me all along, while using my money to stave off ruin.
- 我看到爱迪生的人 - 在哪里?
- I have seen Edison's men. - Where?
在旅馆 我大可以把他们带来
In the hotel, I have a mind to bring them up here.
这么做很不明智 安杰
That would be unwise, Mr. Angier.
你的确是我们最后的金主
It is true that you are our last remaining financier,
但是我们没偷你的钱
but we have not stolen your money.
我的猫
This is my cat.
我说能做出你要的机器是实话
When I told you I could make you a machine, I spoke a simple truth.
那机器为什么没有用?
Why isn't it working?
科学不是绝对
Because exact science, Mr. Angier,
它充满变数
is not an exact science.
机器不一定能正常运作
The machine simply does not operate as expected.
- 需要进行更多实验 - 我的高帽在哪里?
- It requires further examination. - So where did my top hat go?
就在这里
Nowhere.
我们试了十几次
We tried the damn thing a dozen times.
帽子一直在这里
The hat went nowhere.
我们必须试不同的东西
We need to try different material.
才可能有不同的结果
It may provoke a different result.
好的
Great.
我的猫出了事你要负责 博士
You are responsible for whatever happens to this animal, doctor.
我只希望我的钱
I hope whatever you were really doing with my money
花得很值得 泰斯拉先生
was more worthwhile, Mr. Tesla.
艾利!
Alley!
那么说机器真的有用?
So the machine was working?
我没去检查 因为帽子都没动
I never checked the calibration, 'cause the hat never moved.
事情总是很难如你所愿
These things never quite work as you expect them to.
这也是科学原则
That's one of the principal beauties of science.
我要花几个星期解决问题
I'll need a couple of weeks to iron out the problems with the machine.
好了就通知你
We'll send word when it's ready.
别忘了你的帽子
Don't forget your hat.
- 哪一顶是我的? - 都是你的 安杰先生
- Well, which one is mine? - They are all your hats.
你穿这件新衣服好漂亮哦
You look so pretty in this new dress of yours.
- 我们要去动物园吗? - 不 爸爸有别的事情要办
- Are we going to the zoo? - No, remember daddy has some errands to run.
- 但你答应过我的 - 是吗?
- But you promised. - I promised, did I?
那就去动物园吧
Then go to the zoo, we shall.
我先去办事 马上就回来
Daddy will go run his errands, and I'll be back before you know it.
你去准备好 我们去看黑猩猩
So you go get ready. We'll go see those chimpanzees.
莎拉... 你在做什么?
Sarah... what are you doing?
我们各自有沉迷的事情
Each of us have our vices.
莎拉 不管你怎么想...
Sarah, whatever you may think...
...你唯一的对手是我们的女儿
...your only competition for my affections is our little girl.
我爱你 永远爱你
I love you. I will always love you
我只爱你
and you alone.
- 你今天是真心的 - 一点也没错
- You mean it today. - Absolutely.
当你骗我会让我更痛苦
Which makes it so much harder when you don't.
又要买东西 她真是爱钱
More shopping. She does love the smell of money.
女儿想去动物园 你带她去吧 好吗?
The little lady wants to go to the zoo, so I thought you could take her, yeah?
不然我明天可以带她去
I mean, I can do it tomorrow, if not.
还有... 莎拉
And, uh... Sarah,
她已经知道了
she knows.
她知道事情有点不对劲
Uh, at least she knows that something is not right,
请你尽量帮我安抚她的情绪
so if you can just do whatever you can to help me.
说服她我是真的爱她
Talk to her, just convince her that I do love her.
佛迪 怎么了?
What is it, Freddie?
别这样叫我 拜托
Listen, don't call me that, please.
没事 只是有时 有时我觉得很内疚
It's nothing. It's just that sometimes it seems wrong.
我说过 跟我一起时 你的心里只能有我
I told you, when you're with me, you're with me.
你回家再想你的家人
Leave your family at home where they belong.
我一直在试 我一直在试 我很努力
I'm trying. I'm trying, Olivia.
- 我要换衣服了 - 好
- I'll get dressed. - Yeah.
我看见法隆在附近晃
I saw Fallon hanging around again.
我对他不太信任
There's something about that man I don't trust.
你信任我吗? 那就信任法隆
You trust me? Then trust Fallon.
他保护我在乎的东西
He protects the things that I care about.
很遗憾你要离开了 安先生
We're sorry to see you go, Mr. Angier.
真遗憾泰斯拉也要离开
We were sorry to see Mr. Tesla leave, as well.
他对这地方贡献良多
He's very good to Colorado Springs.
安先生
Mr. Angier,
我没告诉爱迪生手下有关箱子的事
I didn't think it was necessary to tell Edison's men about the box.
什么箱子?
What box?
很抱歉离开之前没向你道别
I apologize for leaving without saying goodbye.
但我在这里已经不受欢迎
But I seem to have outstayed my welcome in Colorado.
科学和工业界不能容忍前卫科技
The truly extraordinary is not permitted in science and industry.
大概只有你的魔术能受到肯定
Perhaps you'll find more luck in your field,
观众喜欢解不开的谜
where people are happy to be mystified.
你会在箱子里找到你要的
You will find what you are looking for in this box.
艾利写了详细的使用说明书
Alley has written you a thorough set of instructions.
我对你只有一个建议
I add only one suggestion on using the machine.
毁了这具机器
Destroy it.
将它丢进最深的海底
Drop it to the bottom of the deepest ocean.
它只会带给你不幸
Such a thing will bring you only misery.
如泰斯拉所料 我无视他的警告
Tesla's warning is as unheeded as he knew it would be.
今天我要测试机器
Today I tested the machine. Taking precautions in case
预防它运作时出问题
Tesla hadn't ironed out the kinks in its operation.
如果出事
But if it went wrong,
我不想那样过活
I would not want to live like that for long.
这就是偷天换日的步骤 我要遗弃你了 波登
But here at the turn, I must leave you, Borden.
没错 就是你 波登
Yes, you, Borden,
坐在牢房
sitting there in your cell,
读着我的日记 因为谋杀我
reading my diary, awaiting your death,
等待死亡的来临
for my murder.
安杰的日记 那是假的
Angier's journal, that gesture of good faith, that's a fake.
我向你保证是真的
I assure you, it's not.
来历很清楚 没有疑问
The provenance of the journal is clear and under no doubt.
比对之后证实是安杰的笔迹
And it's written in Angier's own hand, for which we have numerous examples.
无所谓了
It don't matter.
这是我的秘诀
So my tricks.
- 全部的戏法 - 包括移形遁影术?
- All of them. - Including The Transported Man?
- 卡德洛爵士会很高兴 - 他不会的
- Lord Caldlow will be very pleased. - No, he won't.
因为不完整
They're not complete.
只有以虚代实和偷天换日
It's just the pledge and the turn for each.
没有惊天动地的秘诀 根本就一文不值
Without the prestige for these tricks, these are worthless.
没错
Yeah.
想要的话... 就带我女儿来
You get the rest of it... when you bring my daughter here.
我想跟她说再见
I want to say goodbye.
我们必须谈谈 我们必须谈谈
We have to go through it now. We have to go through it now.
听我说 你可以尽管否认
Now, listen to me, deny it all you want.
我根本就不爱奥莉薇雅
Olivia means nothing.
- 奥莉薇雅? - 我需要助手
- Olivia? - I need an assistant.
- 我会告诉她 我会告诉她 - 告诉她什么?
- I'll go to her, I'll tell her. - You'll tell her what?
我知道你的秘密
I know what you really are, Alfred.
- 我知道 - 莎拉 莎拉
- I know. - Sarah, Sarah, Sarah.
- 我再也无法隐瞒下去 - 别胡说八道
- I can't keep it in. - You can't talk like this.
- 不 不 - 莎拉 住嘴! 莎拉 住嘴!
- No. No. - Sarah, shut up! Sarah, shut up!
我不想再听了 你不能这样
I don't want to hear it anymore. You can't talk like this.
你瞒不住的 因为我知道
You can't hide it anymore, because I know, Alfred, I know.
我知道你的真面目 艾佛
I know what you really are, Alfred.
我不能这样过活
I can't live like this.
你觉得我可以这样过活?
Oh, well, you think I can live like this?
我很享受这种生活吗?
You think I bloody enjoy living like this?
我们有房子 有女儿 我们结婚了
We have this beautiful house, lovely little girl, we're married.
你的生活有什么不好?
What is so wrong with your life?
我不要这种生活!
Alfred, I can't live like this!
那你到底要我怎么样?
Well, what do you want from me?
我... 我要...
I... I want...
我要你... 对我诚实
I want you to be... honest with me.
不耍魔术
No tricks.
不说谎话
No lies.
没有秘密
And no secrets.
你... 你爱我吗?
Do you... do you love me?
今天不爱
Not today.
我不爱你
No.
艾德威驰街230号
伦敦
是谁?
Who's there?
我来找位老朋友
I'm looking for an old friend.
听说有一场表演 不错的小戏院
I heard about a booking, nice little theater,
- 魔术界的新秀 - 你回来了
- good up-and-coming magician. - You're back.
见到你真好 约翰
It's good to see you, John.
不错的排练场
Good rehearsal space.
瞎子助手 我喜欢
Blind stagehands, I like it.
你一向都很会耍宣传噱头
You always had a good eye for publicity.
我需要你的帮忙
I need your help, John.
我最后的表演 限定场次
It's my last show. A limited engagement.
你最后的表演?
Your last show?
一位智者说着魔是年轻人的游戏
A wise man once told me obsession was a young man's game.
我差不多完成了 只剩一件事
I'm almost done. There's one thing left.
真正的移形遁影术
The Real Transported Man.
你想要为它设计一场表演?
You want to design a show around it?
我不要你在幕后 这次我要你在外面办事
I don't want you backstage I need you in front managing.
我要你动用你所有的关系
Call in any favors or connections you have left
敲定表演场地
to get us the right booking.
你要哪一种剧院?
What sort of booking you after?
波登会注意到的大剧院
The sort that Borden can't ignore.
能再见到你真是我的荣幸
Oh, what an honor it is to see you again, sir.
你说有一个魔术会让我很感兴趣
You told me you only wanted to show me one trick that'd pique my interest.
- 非常巧妙的魔术 - 幸会了 艾克曼先生
- It's a very clever trick. - Pleased to meet you, Mr. Ackerman.
彼此彼此 开始吧 各位?
Likewise, I'm sure. Let's get on, shall we?
开动机器了 先生们
Turn it on, gentlemen.
很漂亮
Very pretty.
就这样? 他就这样消失了?
That's it, Cutter? He simply disappears?
这不是魔术啊! 他必须回来啊!
That's not a trick. He has to come back.
- 他必须... - 惊天动地?
- There has to be a... - A prestige?
没错
Exactly.
原谅我
Pardon me.
很难得见到...
It's very rare to see...
...真正的魔术
...real magic.
我有很多年没见到...
It's been many years since...
有兴趣帮助我们吗?
Are you interested in helping us?
当然... 不过你得稍微包装一下
Yes... but you'll have to dress it up a little.
加一点伪装
Disguise it.
让观众有怀疑的理由
Give them enough reason to doubt it.
你都没谈到莎拉 半句也没有
You haven't spoken about her, Freddie, not once.
我们为什么要谈她?
Why would I talk about her to you, hm?
她曾是你生命的一部分 现在她死了
Because she was a part of your life and now she's gone.
她自杀前一天说她想见我
You know, the day before she killed herself she said she wanted to meet me.
她想告诉我关于你的事
That she had something to tell me about you.
但是我没胆量 不敢去见她
I was such a coward, I couldn't bring myself to face her.
不过...
But...
...她想跟我说什么?
...what would she have said?
你想知道我的真相?
You want to know the truth about me?
真相是...
The truth is that...
...我从来没爱过莎拉
...I never loved Sarah.
我不爱她
I never loved her.
你娶了她 你们有个孩子
You married her, you had a child with her.
那是一半的我 有一半是我...
Yes. Part of me. Part of me did, but...
...另一半不是我
...the other part didn't.
这个我遇见了你 坐在你面前
The part that found you, the part that's sitting here right now.
我爱的是你 奥莉维亚 我爱你
I love you. No, Olivia, I love you.
这才是真相
That's the truth.
这个真相才重要
That is the truth that matters.
你也很可能在另一家餐厅
You could be in some other restaurant with some other woman right now,
对别的女人这么说我
talking about me that way.
- 不会 - 你会的
- No. - Yes.
你冷酷得真没人性
It's inhuman to be so cold.
他回来了
He's back.
事隔两年 他有了新魔术
After two years, he's got a new trick.
大家都说是前所未见的表演
They're saying it's the best London's ever seen.
你该看看你的表情 教授
You should see the look on your face, Professor.
你应该去见他
You should go to him.
你们俩是绝配
You two deserve each other.
有人订下我的剧院 莫斯科芭蕾舞团要演到明年
But I'm afraid I'm booked. The Moscow Ballet plays through next year.
取消他们的演出 我要做一百场演出 不多也不少
Then get rid of them. There will be 100 performances, no more, no less.
每周五场 没有下午场
Five performances a week, no matinees.
这是门票的价格 祝愉快
That's what you'll charge for each ticket. Good day.
各位 我今晚的第一个表演非常危险
Ladies and gentlemen, my first trick of the evening involves considerable risk.
要是有观众
Anyone in the audience
怕看到有人被淹死
who would be irrevocably damaged by seeing a man drown
请离席
should leave now.
教我这招魔术的女孩
When I tell you the lady who taught me this illusion
在表演时溺死
actually died performing it,
你们应该了解这有多危险
you'll understand the seriousness of the dangers involved.
开始吧
Let's begin.
我在旅行中看见了未来
In my travels, I have seen the future.
非常奇异的未来
And it is a strange future, indeed.
各位先生女士 这世界正面临
The world, ladies and gentlemen,
崭新的
is on the brink of new
骇人的可能性
and terrifying possibilities.
你们即将目睹的不是魔术
What you're about to witness is not magic.
而是纯粹的科学见证
It's purely science.
尽管上台来
I'd like to invite you to come up on stage now
亲自检查这台机器
so that you can examine the machine for yourselves.
人类的成就
Man's reach
远远超过想像力
exceeds his imagination.
太棒了!
Bravo!
一百场演出 为什么?
One hundred performances. Why?
受限于手法?
Does his method dictate that?
或是宣传伎俩? 是吗?
Is it a publicity move? What is it?
他只是个瘪脚的魔术师
He's a no-talent magician, and they call him
凭什么被称为英国顶尖大师?
the bloody best in England. Why?
一秒钟移形五十码! 一秒钟!
Fifty yards in a second! In a second!
我只知道他用暗门
And all that we know is he uses a trap door.
太厉害了! 舞台底下有什么玄机?
Brilliant! What is going on under that stage?
你为什么猜不到?
Why can't you out-think him?
每晚演出后 都偷偷把它运走?
They do this every night, after each performance. Yeah?
呃
Huh.
伟大的丹顿
真正的
瞬间
转移
仅
场
我们没辙了
We're done.
好吗?
All right?
让他变他的
Let him have his trick.
我不要他的秘诀
I don't need his secret.
所以...
So...
...别去了 离他远点
...don't go back there, you leave him alone.
我们俩... 都离他远一点
Both of us... just leave him alone.
我们输了
We're done.
我说过 约翰
I told you, John.
我不要你到后台
I don't want you backstage on this one.
尽管上台
I would like to invite you onstage now
亲自检查这台机器
so that you can examine the machine for yourselves.
- 你想去哪里... - 我是表演的一部分 猪头
- Hey, where do you think...? - I'm part of the bloody act, you fool.
那是谁?
Who was that?
嘿! 钥匙在哪里?!
Hey! Where's the bloody key?!
钥匙在哪里?!
Where's the bloody key?!
钥匙在哪里?! 他快淹死了!
Where's the bloody key?! He's bloody drowning!
撑着点!
Hold on!
你做了什么?
What have you done?
艾佛波登 你被判谋杀罗伯特安杰有罪
Alfred Borden, you have been found guilty of the murder of Robert Angier.
将被判处绞刑至死
You will be hanged by the neck until dead.
愿主让你的灵魂安息
May the Lord have mercy on your soul.
柯特先生?
Mr. Cutter?
我是欧文
Owens.
谢谢你赶来 欧文先生
Oh, thank you for coming, Mr. Owens.
我必须处理安杰的魔术道具
It has fallen to me to dispose of Mr. Angier's equipment.
但我发现多半都
But I notice from this manifest
被卡德洛爵士买走了
that Lord Caldlow has purchased the bulk of the items.
你想知道东西要送到哪里...
Mr. Cutter, if you need to know where to deliver these items...
不 只是有一件道具
No, it's just there is one particular item,
就是这一件
this item, in fact,
- 我想要... - 你想要...
- I would like to... - You would like to...
...买下来
...buy.
- 你想买? - 对 没错
- Buy yourself? - Yeah, I suppose so.
- 就是这台机器? - 是的
- This is the machine? - Yes.
恐怕卡德洛爵士
Well, I'm afraid Lord Caldlow was adamant
会不肯割爱
about purchasing this particular item.
我能跟卡爵士私下谈一下吗?
Do you think I could talk to Lord Caldlow in person?
想都别想
Out of the question, I'm afraid.
不过
Of course,
如果你在运送过程
I suppose if, in the course of your delivery arrangements,
无意间遇见他 我也不能阻止你们说话
your paths were to cross, I can't stop you speaking your mind.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 你还在啊 波登? - 是啊
- Still here, Borden? - For now.
你有访客 卡德洛爵士
You got a visitor. Lord Caldlow.
带着一个小女孩
With a little girl.
洁丝?
Jess?
亲爱的
Hello, my love.
你好吗? 我好想你哦
How are you? I've missed you so much.
法隆也想你 我们都想你
Fallon's missed you too. We both have.
爸爸 我能进去吗?
Daddy, can I come in there?
现在不行 不行 甜心
Not right now. Not right now, darling.
放心 一切都不会有事的
No, but everything is gonna be all right.
你一定是卡德洛爵士?
You must be Lord Caldlow?
卡洛德 我就是 我一直都是
Caldlow. Yes, I am. I always have been.
他们还替你戴手铐啊 艾佛
They flatter you with all those chains.
他们难道不知道 你没有小皮球绝对逃不了吗?
Don't they know you can't escape without your rubber ball?
我把你... 从水箱拉出来
I pulled you out... out of that tank.
我只想证明我比你厉害
All I wanted to do was prove that I was a better magician.
你却不放过我
But you couldn't leave me alone.
我不知道你做了什么
I don't know what you've done.
不过你不怕杀生弄脏手了 是吗?
But you're not afraid to get your hands dirty anymore, are you?
是啊 再也不怕了 而且我赢了
No, not anymore. And I win.
因为没有人在乎消失的人
No one cares about the man in the box, the man who disappears.
你赢了?
You win?
这不是对决 事关我女儿的未来
This ain't a bloody competition anymore. This is my little girl's life.
你不能把她扯进来
And don't you dare put her in the middle of this.
我了解心爱的人
Oh, I know how hard it is to have someone so special
被人夺走的感受 对吗 波登?
taken away from you, don't I, Borden?
你死了就不能带她走了 不是吗?
And you can't take it with you, now, can you?
我会好好照顾她的
Oh, she'll be looked after.
再见了 来吧 亲爱的
Goodbye, Professor. Come on, darling.
不 别走 别走 亲爱的
No, no, no, no, stop, my darling.
你瞧
Look, here.
这是你一直想要的东西 一切都是为了这个
That's what you're after. That's what this is about.
拿去吧
Take it.
- 你的秘诀? - 对
- Your secret? - Yeah.
你一直都比我出色 我们都很清楚
You always were the better magician. We both know that.
但是不管你有什么秘诀 你得承认
Whatever your secret was, you have to agree,
我的魔术比你厉害
mine is better.
别这么做 别这么做 洁丝 洁丝!
Don't do this. Don't do this, Angier. Jess, Jess!
洁丝 我答应要带你回家 我保证
Jess, I'm gonna take you home soon. I promise.
- 拜托 - 我保证 瞧!
- For God's sake. - I promise. Look!
我保证 我爱你 洁丝
I promise. I love you, Jess.
我爱你
I love you.
- 来吧 - 我爱你
- Come on. - I love you.
我爱你 洁丝
I love you, Jess.
安杰! 安杰!
Angier! Angier!
你以为这地方困得住我吗?
What, do you think this place can hold me?
安杰! 我会被吊死!
Angier! They're gonna bloody hang me!
你可以阻止他们!
And you can put a stop to this now!
听着! 听着! 那个人...
Listen! Listen! That man...
听着 那个人是大家以为被我杀死的人!
Listen, that man is the one I'm in for killing!
听着! 他没死 我就没罪!
Listen! If he's alive, I'm not guilty!
- 我没罪! - 我才不管!
- I'm not guilty! - I don't care!
- 抓住他 - 安杰!
- Get hold of him. - Angier!
出去玩吧
Run along now.
老爷 有位先生在等你
Sir, there's a gentleman waiting.
- 老天爷 - 你好 柯特
- Dear God. - Hello, Cutter.
你还活着
You're still alive.
你怎么会没死?
How is it you're still alive?
我看到你的尸体
I saw you on a slab, for God's sake.
- 孩子 - 晚安 先生
- Child. - Good night, sir.
晚安 洁丝
Good night, Jess.
我见过她
I've seen her before.
她在法庭跟...
I saw her in court with...
...法隆在一起
...Fallon.
- 你做了什么? - 她需要有人照顾
- What have you done? - She needs looking after.
她需要她的父亲
She needs her father.
你害他被处死 我成了帮凶
You're letting him hang, and I helped you.
我是来求卡爵士让我毁了机器的
I came here to beg Lord Caldlow to let me destroy that machine.
我再也不会求你做任何事了
I am not going to beg you for anything.
用不着 我再也不会使用它了
You don't have to. I'm gonna make sure it is never used again.
那么 卡德洛爵士...
Then, Lord Caldlow...
...你要我把它运到哪里?
...where do you want me to deliver it?
我的剧院 和其它道具放在一起
My theater. It belongs with the prestige materials.
约翰 我试着不牵涉到你
John, I tried not to involve you.
所以...
So...
咱们俩要分道扬镖了
We go alone now.
咱们俩
Both of us.
只是我不能活得像你一样久
I mean, I don't have as far to go as you.
不能
No.
你是对的 我不该去招惹他
You were right. I should have left him to his damn trick.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我对很多事都感到抱歉
I'm sorry for a lot of things.
我对不起莎拉
I'm sorry about Sarah.
我不是要故意伤害她 我不是故意的
Didn't mean to hurt her, I didn't.
你要好好活下去 好吗? 替咱们俩活下去
You go live your life in full now, all right? You live for both of us.
永别了
Goodbye.
你在仔细看吗?
Are you watching closely?
放在这里
Put it down on the end.
想想你的伟大成就
Take a minute to consider your achievement.
我说过一个水手
I once told you about a sailor
形容溺死的感觉
who described drowning to me.
你说他觉得就像回到家一样
Yes, he said it was like going home.
我说谎 他说痛苦至极
I was lying. He said it was agony.
艾佛波登 今天 我以英王
Alfred Borden, this day, in the name of the king
与最高法庭之名
and the High Court of England,
将你判处死刑
you will meet your end.
没人在乎消失的人
No one cares about the man in the box.
柯特?
Cutter?
柯特!
Cutter!
你有什么遗言?
Do you have anything to say?
天灵灵地灵灵
Abracadabra.
兄弟? 双胞胎兄弟?
A brother? A twin?
你伪装成法隆?
You were Fallon.
- 那么长时间? - 不
- The whole time? - No.
我们都是法隆
We were both Fallon.
也都是波登
We were both Borden.
你是消失的那个人?
Were you the one who went into the box?
还是现身的那个人?
Or the one who came back out?
我们会轮流
We took turns.
重点就在于我们互换身分
The trick is where we would swap.
柯特早就知道了 柯特早就知道了
Cutter knew. Cutter knew.
但我说这太简单 太容易了
But I told him it was too simple, too easy.
不
No.
或许很简单 但是不容易
Simple, maybe, but not easy.
两个人共享一个生活并不容易
There's nothing easy about two men sharing one life.
我不懂 怎么又流血了?
I don't understand, how it can be bleeding again?
那...奥莉薇雅呢 你的妻子呢?
Wha... What about Olivia and your wife?
我们各有所爱
We each loved one of them.
我爱莎拉
I loved Sarah.
他爱奥莉薇雅
He loved Olivia.
我们各拥有一半的生活
We each had half of a full life,
这样对我们已经足够...
really, which was enough for us...
...只不过
...just.
对她们却不够
But not for them.
看 自我牺牲 罗伯特
See, sacrifice, Robert,
才是精彩魔术的代价
that's the price of a good trick.
但是你完全不能体会 不是吗?
You wouldn't know anything about that, would you?
我也... 我也做了牺牲
I've... I've made sacrifices.
- 没有 - 我有
- No. - Yes.
偷学别人不用花任何力气
It takes nothing to steal another man's work.
我尽了一切努力
Yeah, it takes everything.
不 等等 我是...
No, no, wait, I'm not...
这需要勇气
It took courage.
我每晚都要鼓起勇气走进机器
It took courage to climb into that machine every night,
不知道...
not knowing...
...自己会消失不见...
...if I'd be the man in the box...
...或是神奇现身
...or in the prestige.
你想看看...
Do you want to see...
...我的代价吗?
...what it cost me?
你还没看过这地方吧?
You didn't see where you are, did you?
你看 你看
Look. Look.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你到了世界另一端
You went halfway around the world.
花了一大笔钱
You spent a fortune.
做出可怕的事
You did terrible things.
真正可怕的事 罗伯特
Really terrible things, Robert.
结果什么都没得到
And all for nothing.
什么都没得到?
For nothing?
对
Yeah.
你永远不懂...
You never understood...
...我们为什么要变魔术
...why we did this.
观众知道真相
The audience knows the truth.
现实既残酷
The world is simple.
又悲惨
It's miserable.
没有奇迹... 没有魔法
Solid... Solid all the way through.
但是如果你能骗倒他们
But if you could fool them,
即使只有一秒钟...
even for a second...
...就能让他们惊叹
...then you could make them wonder.
然后你就能...
And then you...
然后你就能看到
Then you got to see something
非常特别的事
very special.
你真的不知道吗
You really don't know.
那就是...
It was...
...那就是观众脸上的表情
...it was the look on their faces.
每一场魔术表演都有三个步骤
Every magic trick consists of three parts, or acts.
第一个步骤是"以虚代实"
The first part is called "the pledge."
魔术师先秀出一个真实的东西
The magician shows you something ordinary.
第二个步骤是"偷天换日"
The second act is called "the turn."
魔术师利用这个普通的东西
The magician takes the ordinary something
做出令人叹为观止的表演
and makes it into something extraordinary.
但是你还不会鼓掌 因为把东西变不见
But you wouldn't clap yet, because making something disappear
还不够 你必须把它变回来
isn't enough. You have to bring it back.
现在你想找出秘诀
Now you're looking for the secret.
但是绝对找不到 因为你没真正在看
But you won't find it, because, of course, you're not really looking.
你并不是真的想知道
You don't really want to work it out.
你想要被骗
You want to be fooled.